[{"question":"For orthorhombic system axial ratios are a = bxcam * dthc","a":"alpha = beta = gamma = 90 deg","b":"alpha = beta = gamma = 90 deg","c":"alpha = B = y = 90 deg beta = 90 deg","d":"alpha= beta ne gamma = 90 deg","hint":"","correct":"b"},{"question":"The space lattice of graphite is","a":"cubic","b":"tetragonal","c":"rhombic","d":"hexagonal","hint":"","correct":"d"},{"question":"Example of molecular solid is","a":"SO,(s)","b":"SC","c":"C(graphite)","d":"NiCI","hint":"","correct":"a"},{"question":"Which of the following is not a crystalline solid?","a":"KCl","b":"CCl","c":"Glass","d":"Rhombic S","hint":"","correct":"c"},{"question":"Which of the following conditions favours the existence  27  of a substance in the solid state?","a":"High temperature","b":"Low temperature","c":"High thermal energy","d":"Weak cohensive forces","hint":"","correct":"b"},{"question":"Ifz is the number of atoms in the unit cell that represents the closest packing sequence... ABC ABC. the number 29  of tetrahedral voids in the unit cell is equal to","a":"z","b":"2z","c":"z/2","d":"z/4","hint":"","correct":"b"},{"question":"The C * a ^ 27 * andF located in CaF, crystalrespectively at face centred cubic lattice points and in","a":"tetrahedral voids","b":"half of tetrahedral voids","c":"octahedral voids","d":"half of octahedral voids","hint":"","correct":"a"},{"question":"The coordination number in hep is","a":"6","b":"12","c":"18","d":"24","hint":"","correct":"b"},{"question":"Which is not correct about the Schottky defects","a":"Both cations and anions are missing from their lattice sites without affecting the stoichiometry of","b":"Because of the presence of holes the lattice","c":"The presence of holes causes the density of the","d":"The defect increases the electrical conductivity of  the solid due to migration of the ions into the holes","hint":"","correct":"b"},{"question":"Agl crystallises in zine blende structure with Iions at lattice points. What fraction of tetrahedral voids is occupied","a":"25%","b":"50%","c":"100 \\%","d":"75 \\%","hint":"","correct":"b"},{"question":"Sodium metal crystallizes in a body centred cubic lattice with a unit cell edge of 4.29A. The radius of sodium atom","a":"5.72A","b":"0.93A","c":"186A","d":"3.22A","hint":"","correct":"c"},{"question":"Which of the following is a network solid","a":"S*O_{2} (solid","b":"- I_{2}","c":"Diamond","d":"H,O (ice)","hint":"","correct":"c"},{"question":"F-centre is","a":"anion vacancy occupied by unpaired electron","b":"anion vacancy occupied by electron.","c":"cation vacancy occupeid by electron.","d":"anion present in interstitial site.","hint":"","correct":"a"},{"question":"Graphite cannot be classified as","a":"conducting solid","b":"network solid","c":"covalent solid","d":"ionic solid","hint":"","correct":"d"},{"question":"An example of a covalent crystalline solid is:","a":"St","b":"Al","c":"NaF","d":"Ar","hint":"","correct":"a"},{"question":"Which of the following compounds is a good conductor  of electricity in solution state?  ","a":"Covalent","b":"Molecular","c":"Metallic","d":"lonic","hint":"","correct":"d"},{"question":"A solid with high electrical and thermal conductivity is","a":"St","b":"Li","c":"NaC","d":"Ice","hint":"","correct":"b"},{"question":"Solids which do not show different directions are called same physical properties in","a":"Pseudo solids","b":"Isotropic solids","c":"Polyunnplus solids","d":"Anisotropic solids","hint":"","correct":"d"},{"question":"In h.c.p of A. of tetrahedralWhat is the formula for compound: voids are occupied by B.","a":"A,B,","b":"A2B3","c":"AB2","d":"A2B","hint":"","correct":"b"},{"question":"Which of the following statements is true for ionic solids  ?","a":"Ionic solide are soluble in CCI, CH, etc","b":"Under the electric field cations and anions acquiretranslatory motion in opposite directions","c":"Structural units have strong electrostatic force of","d":"Structural units have dipole-dipole interactions","hint":"","correct":"c"},{"question":"Crystals can be classified into basic crystal lattice, equal","a":"7","b":"4","c":"14","d":"2","hint":"","correct":"a"},{"question":"The number of atoms present in a hexagonal close-packed","a":"4","b":"6","c":"8","d":"12","hint":"","correct":"b"},{"question":"If the radius of the anion in an ionic solid is 200 pm, what would be the radius of the cation that fits exactly into a","a":"146.4pm","b":"82.8pm","c":"45pm","d":"None of these","hint":"","correct":"a"},{"question":"Which colour is observed when ZnO is heated","a":"Yellow","b":"Violet","c":"Groen","d":"Blue","hint":"","correct":"a"},{"question":"In which of the following pairs of structures, tetrahedralwell as octahedral holes are found","a":"bee and fee","b":"hep and simple cubic","c":"hen and cen","d":"bee and hen","hint":"","correct":"c"},{"question":"In NaCl crystal cach Clion  is surrounded by","a":"6Na^ prime prime mas","b":"Clion  is surrounded by (b) 6Na^ prime prime mas  64. Whic  (a) 4N a^ +","c":"2N a^ - ions","d":"1Nations","hint":"","correct":"a"},{"question":"In face centred cubic arrangement of A and B atoms, whose A atoms are at the corners of the unit cell and B atoms al the face centres and A atoms are missing from two comers in each unit cell. What is the formula of the compound","a":"A*B_{4}","b":"A*B_{3}","c":"A_{1}*B","d":"AB","hint":"","correct":"b"},{"question":"In the unit cell of KCI (NaCl type), CT ions constitute cep and Kions fall into the octahedral holes. These holes are:","a":"one at the centre and 6 at the centres of the faces","b":". Whic  (b) one at the centre and 12 at the centres of the edges","c":"at the centres of 8 small cubes forming the unit cell  (a)  (d","d":"none of these","hint":"","correct":"b"},{"question":"Potassium fluoride has NaCl type structure. What is the distance between K' and F ions if cell edge is 'a' cm.","a":"2cm","b":"a/2 cm","c":"4 cm","d":"a4 cm","hint":"","correct":"b"},{"question":"The number of atoms in 100 g of an fee crystal with density, d-10 g/cm and cell edge equal to 100 pm, is equal to","a":"1×1025","b":"2×1025","c":"3×105","d":"4×105","hint":"","correct":"d"},{"question":"The radi of Na\" and CT ionsand 181 pm  respectively. The edge length of NaCl unit cell is are 95 pm and 181 pm","a":"276pm","b":"138pm","c":"552 pm","d":"415pm","hint":"","correct":"c"},{"question":"Which of the following statements for crystals havingSchottky defect is not correct?","a":"Schottky defect arises due to the absence of a cation  and anion from the position which it is expected to","b":"Schottky defect are more common in ionic compounds","c":"The density of the crystals having Schottky defect  is larger than that of the perfect crystal","d":"The crystal having Schottky de","hint":"","correct":"c"},{"question":"Which of the following defects de","a":"Frankel","b":"Metal excess","c":"co-ordination","d":"co-ordination","hint":"","correct":"a"},{"question":"Dopping of AgCl crystals with CaCl, results","a":"Schottky defect","b":"Frenkel defect","c":"Substitutional cation vacancy","d":"Formation of F-centres","hint":"","correct":"c"},{"question":"Due to Frenkel defect, the density of the ionic solids","a":"Increases","b":"Decreases","c":"Does not change","d":"Changes","hint":"","correct":"c"},{"question":"Which of the following is true about the value of refractiveindex of quartz glass","a":"Same in all directions","b":"Different in different directions","c":"Cannot be measured","d":"Always zero","hint":"","correct":"a"},{"question":"Iodine molecules are held in the crystals lattice by","a":"London forces","b":"dipole-dipole interactions","c":"covalent bonds","d":"coulombic forces","hint":"","correct":"a"},{"question":"Which of the following is not the characteristic of ionic solid.","a":"Very low value of electrical conductivity in the molten","b":"Brittle nature","c":"Very strong forces of interactions","d":"Anisotropic nature","hint":"","correct":"a"},{"question":"Cations are present in the interstitial sites in.","a":"Frenkel defect","b":"Schottky defect","c":"vacancy defect","d":"metal deficiency defect","hint":"","correct":"a"},{"question":"In which of the following pair, most efficient WJEE  packing is","a":"hep and bee","b":"hep and cep","c":"bee and cep","d":"bec and simple cubic cell","hint":"","correct":"b"}]